SARA CHOI - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dunwoody, GA | 310-904-3100 | choisara2010@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

SUMMARY

Highly motivated and driven Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Management, problem-solving, attention to detail, and multitasking are all skills honed through 12 years within the hospitality industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, Github, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code

Additional Skills: Project Management, Training, and Development.

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful

Software Engineering Program

Remote

09/2022 - Present

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3,
 React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
 - Study Tool Application | <u>Link</u>:
 - Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
 - Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
 - Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
 - Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML, and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.
 - Encryption/Decryption Application | <u>Link</u>:
 - Built to be an encryption/decryption application to communicate and read top-secret messages.
 - Created utilizing the test-driven development method.
 - Technology: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, Node.is, Bootstrap, Mocha, Chai.
 - Library Application | <u>Link</u>:
 - Assembled the functionality for an application that allows users to search, review and check out books from their local neighborhood.
 - Created search and sorting functions to allow users to know what books were available and their ratings.
 - Coded using JavaScript functions that are built to enable the expansion of the library with little to no need for code refactoring.
 - Technology: JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js

JoJo's Beloved Cocktail Lounge

Atlanta, GA

General Manager

10/2019 - 11/2022

- Provided exceptional upscale and memorable experience for guests including VIP members in an exclusive speakeasy that held up to 250 guests.
- Created a VIP Membership program and created the reservation system and procedures.
- Planned multiple events weekly for parties, industry nights, and educational nights held every Monday working with other Brand Ambassadors to represent products.
- Used kanban boards for project management and created an excel sheet to track our inventory and predict supplies.

Barmetrix Los Angeles, CA
Consultant 11/2018 – 12/2020

- Coached over 300 bar/restaurant operations teams in Los Angeles, providing expertise in solving some of the most common issues in hospitality businesses worldwide today.
- Created the Guest Service Evaluations Program for Barmetrix LA.

Consulted with multiple restaurant/bar groups in LA, providing data on Cost of Goods, Profit and Loss,
 Variance, and more to drive up the company's profit and assist in creating an elevated guest environment.

Improved Gross Sales for business by at least 16% after 4 months of consultation.

4100 Bar General Manager

Los Angeles, CA 11/2016 – 12/2019

• Created and maintained positive morale with the bar staff which ensured high levels of customer satisfaction through excellent sales service, seating up to 200 guests.

- Led weekly meetings with at least 5 distribution representatives, choosing products that are featured on the menu based on knowledge of the clientele, and maintaining our inventory of over \$3,000 worth of products.
- Reduced Bar Variance of Loss from 28% to consistently running under 5% Variance of Loss as well as lowering Venue's Cost of Goods Sold from 24% to consistently running around 15%.
- Improved Gross Sales by approximately 18% each year as General Manager.

EDUCATION

Thinkful
Certificate, Software Engineering

Remote 01/2022